Pen, Paint, and Pretzels Records UA068
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Pen, Paint, and Pretzels Records
1930 -- 1980
1900 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Department of Drama and Dance
Pen, Paint and Pretzels
UA068
54.27 Linear Feet
82 Volumes
113 Digital Object(s)
1 Web sites
This collection contains the records of Pen, Paint, and Pretzels.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by 3P's, 2016-2018.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in six series: Scrapbooks, Play Books, and Drama Department records; Production images; Scripts and publicity materials; Web crawls; 2016-2018 accessions; and Unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
Pen, Paint, and Pretzels was founded in 1910 by five members of the class of 1911. The organization's goal was to encourage dramatic interest at Tufts College by the production of original plays by students or graduates of Tufts or Jackson. Pen was to signify the writers, paint the artists, and pretzels the audience. Although prior to 1910 there had been a few drama organizations at Tufts, they were short-lived and generally unsuccessful. In the spring of that year, Clifford Amsden, Walston Brown, Harold Gallupe, Charles Gott, and John Libby came together to form Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, designed to be a more permanent organization. With the help of Professor Leo R. Lewis, the five juniors organized auditions and found a stage space in Jackson Gym. Their first production, "Teamwork," written by Gott and Gallupe, premiered December 15, 1910. By 1912, the founders had graduated, but Pen, Paint, and Pretzels had earned enough money to install lighting and dimmers on the Jackson stage, and was also able to purchase costume and scenery materials. Although the organization did not only perform plays by Tufts authors, Pen, Paint, and Pretzels quickly became very popular around campus, playing to full houses and garnering excellent reviews. With the outbreak of World War I, Pen, Paint, and Pretzels began to take their performances on the road. They performed at nearby barracks for soldiers and did benefit shows to encourage the purchase of war bonds. After the war, Pen, Paint, and Pretzels continued to perform charity shows at locations all around New England. In 1921, future Tufts president Leonard Carmichael was elected president of the organization, and in 1924, their performance of "Romeo and Juliet" was broadcast over AMRAD's station, WGI. It was one of the first times a play was broadcast live over the airwaves. Since 1915, Pen, Paint, and Pretzels worked closely with the Masque, the drama society of Jackson College. The two groups collaborated on many plays, fundraising and holding auditions jointly. Finally, in 1930, the two organizations merged under the Pen, Paint, and Pretzels name, increasing the organization's membership and funding. Since then, Pen, Paint, and Pretzels has remained a co-ed organization. During World War II, Pen, Paint and Pretzels decreased their performances as students concentrated on the war effort. Their performance of "Heavenly Express" in 1941 was interrupted to broadcast Roosevelt's announcement that the Japanese had bombed Pearl Harbor. Immediately following the war, enrollment at Tufts swelled, and demand for seating at Pen, Paint, and Pretzels events greatly increased. For some of its performances, the organization packed up and moved to Pearson Hall in order to accommodate a larger audience. In 1948, the Department of Athletics finally vacated Jackson Gym, which was already informally known as the Tufts Theater. The facility was given over to the Department of Drama and Speech, but early in 1949, the stage was condemned, forcing the department to stage plays on a raised oval in the middle of the gym floor. This new setup was the first appearance of an arena theater in New England. Pen, Paint, and Pretzels productions were photographed for use in "Amerika," a State Department publication about American culture designed for Soviet citizens. Pen, Paint, and Pretzels continued to stage its productions in the Tufts Arena Theater until its destruction in 1991. Drama productions were then moved to the Marston Balch Arena Theater, constructed in the Aidekman Arts Center the same year. The new theater contains state of the art lighting and stage equipment, and is named after a former Pen, Paint, and Pretzels faculty advisor.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of materials relating to the organization Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, also known as 3P's. Most of the materials relate chiefly to individual productions produced or co-produced by Pen, Paint, and Pretzels. Materials include scripts, promptbooks and playbooks, cue sheets, production notes, costume sketches, rehearsal schedules, photographs, programs, fliers, and other promotional materials. The collection also contains materials documenting the organizations history and business, such as their constitution, meeting minutes, scrapbooks, financial documents, correspondence, member and alumni lists, production licenses, production lists, and clippings. There are also materials relating to Torn Ticket II and the Tufts Community Players (originally the Tuft Graduate Dramatic Society) including copies of their constitutions, and materials relating to Alpha Psi Omega, a Dramatic Performance fraternity, which include pledging materials. The collection also contains CDs, DVDs, and mini DVs of 3P's events and productions, historic material related to the 3P's, and a 3P's branded shot glass.
Student life; Student Activities -- Student Government, Clubs, and Organizations; Student Activities -- Performing Arts; Student life
- Scrapbooks, Play Books, and Drama Department records, 1910 -- 1971; 1930 -- 1950; UA068.001.000001; 6.75 Linear Feet; 82 Volumes; 3 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of Pen, Paint and Pretzels scrapbooks, Play Books, and production files, as well as Drama Department records related to co-produced plays. There are eleven scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings of performances, reviews and articles, playbills, letters and some photos all relating to Pen, Paint and Pretzels. Nine of the scrapbooks are from a ten volume run; volume three is missing. Drama Department records document productions put on jointly by the two groups. These records include minutes, news clippings, and individual production files. Other records in this series include a Pen, Paint and Pretzels account book dated 1912-1916 and three Drama Department files relating to Tufts Community Players.
  Arrangement
  Scrapbooks arranged by original volume numbers. Other material in this series is not arranged.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, scrapbook, Vol. I, 1906 -- 1939; UA068.001.001.001 (Box 1)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, scrapbook, Vol. II, 1939 -- 1940; UA068.001.002.001 (Box 2)
    Newspaper clippings, reviews, programs, photos, scripts, and misc. memorabilia
    Pen, Paint, and Pretzels
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, scrapbook, Vol. IV, 1941 -- 1943; UA068.001.003.001 (Box 3)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, Scrapbook, Vol. V, 1943 -- 1945; UA068.001.004.001 (Box 4)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, Scrapbook, Vol. VI, 1945 -- 1947; UA068.001.005.001 (Box 5)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, Scrapbook, Vol. VII, 1947 -- 1949; UA068.001.006.001 (Box 6)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, Scrapbook, Vol. VIII, 1949 -- 1950; UA068.001.007.001 (Box 7)
    Newspaper clippings, reviews, photos, programs, scripts, and misc. memorabilia
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, Scrapbook, Vol. IX, 1950 -- 1952; UA068.001.008.001 (Box 8)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, Scrapbook, Vol. X, 1952 -- 1954; UA068.001.009.001 (Box 9)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, Production Handbook, 1946; UA068.001.010.001 (Box 10)
    Manual listing methods of theatrical production used by the Tufts College Theater; credited to Richard C. Holden.
    Holden, Richard C.; Pen, Paint, and Pretzels
  - Leo Lewis's Pen, Paint, and Pretzels' Scrapbook, 1911 -- 1917; UA068.001.011.001 (Box 11)
    Newspaper clippings, letters, financial records, programs, invoices, and misc. memorabilia
    Lewis, Leo R.; Pen, Paint, and Pretzels
  - Pen, Paint and Pretzels, account book, 1912 -- 1916; UA068.001.012.001 (Box 12)
    financial records
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, scrapbook, 1916 -- 1927; UA068.001.013.001 (Box 13)
    Box 1 of 2. Newspaper clippings, letters, financial records, programs, invoices, and misc. memorabilia.
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels, scrapbook, 1916 -- 1927; UA068.001.014.001 (Box 14)
    Box 2 of 2. Newspaper clippings, letters, financial records, programs, invoices, and misc. memorabilia.
  - Drama Department, PPP: minutes, 1950 -- 1958; UA068.001.015.00001 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department, PPP: minutes, 1958 -- 1962; UA068.001.015.00002 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department PPP: Mock Productions, 1945 -- 1959; UA068.001.015.00003 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department, PPP: news clippings, 1922 -- 1925; UA068.001.015.00004 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department, productions, 1910 -- 1934; UA068.001.015.00005 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department PPP, prize competitions, 1923 -- 1958; UA068.001.015.00006 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department PPP, minutes, 1962 -- 1963; UA068.001.015.00007 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department, Tufts Community Players: general, 1941 -- 1961; UA068.001.015.00008 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department, Tufts Community Players: application, 1948 -- 1949; UA068.001.015.00009 (Box 15)
  - Drama Department, Tufts Community Players: Constitution-minutes, 1951 -- 1964; UA068.001.015.00010 (Box 15)
  - Drama Dept., Rashomon, 1959; UA068.001.016.00001 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., The Diary of Anne Frank, 1960; UA068.001.016.00002 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., Light up the Sky, 1960; UA068.001.016.00003 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., The Would-be Gentleman, 1960; UA068.001.016.00004 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., Summertime, 1961; UA068.001.016.00007 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., Joan of Lorraine, 1962; UA068.001.016.00008 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., Our Town, 1962; UA068.001.017.00002 (Box 17)
  - Drama Dept., The Barber of Seville, 1963; UA068.001.017.00003 (Box 17)
  - Drama Dept., Dark of the Moon, 1963; UA068.001.017.00004 (Box 17)
  - Drama Dept., Queen of the Rebels, 1963; UA068.001.017.00005 (Box 17)
  - Drama Dept., Cock a Doodle Dandy, 1964; UA068.001.017.00006 (Box 17)
  - Drama Dept., King Lear, 1964; UA068.001.018.00001 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., Miss Jairus, 1964; UA068.001.018.00002 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., The Devil's Disciple, 1965; UA068.001.018.00003 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., The House of Bernada Alba, 1965; UA068.001.018.00004 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., Three Sisters, 1965; UA068.001.018.00005 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., The Visit, 1966; UA068.001.018.00006 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., 'Tis a Pity She's a Whore, 1966; UA068.001.018.00007 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., The Devils, 1967; UA068.001.018.00008 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., Antigone, 1968; UA068.001.018.00009 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., Oh What a Lovely War, 1968; UA068.001.018.00010 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., Britannicus, 1969; UA068.001.018.00011 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., A Flea in Her Ear, 1969; UA068.001.018.00012 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., Serjeant Musgrave's Dance, 1969; UA068.001.018.00013 (Box 18)
  - Drama Dept., The Piper of Seville, 1969; UA068.001.019.00001 (Box 19)
  - Drama Dept., Charlie is My Darling, 1970; UA068.001.019.00002 (Box 19)
    - Rehearsal for 'Charlie is My Darling' featuring William Hurt, 1970; UA068.001.019.00002.00001; Duette Photographers (Box 19)
      Theater; Plays; Actors; Students; Hurt, William; Pen, Paint, and Pretzels; Dept. of Drama
  - Drama Dept., Jimmy Shine, 1970; UA068.001.019.00003 (Box 19)
    - William Hurt and two unidentified student actors in 'Jimmy Shine', 1970; UA068.001.019.00003.00001; Duette Photographers (Box 19)
  - Drama Dept., The Killer, 1971; UA068.001.019.00004 (Box 19)
  - Drama Dept., The Poets Papers, 1971; UA068.001.019.00005 (Box 19)
  - Drama Dept., Rosencrantz and Guildenstern, 1970; UA068.001.019.00006 (Box 19)
    - William Hurt in 'Rosencrantz and Guildenstern', 1970; UA068.001.019.00006.00001; Unknown (Box 19)
      Theater; Actors; Students; Plays; Hurt, William; Pen, Paint, and Pretzels; Dept. of Drama
  - Drama Dept., Women Beware Women, 1971; UA068.001.019.00007 (Box 19)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Paths of Glory, 1935 -- 1936; UA068.001.024.001 (Box Volume 24)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Murray Hill, 1935 -- 1936; UA068.001.025.001 (Box Volume 25)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Dr. Knock, 1935 -- 1936; UA068.001.026.001 (Box Volume 26)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Squaring the Circle, 1936 -- 1937; UA068.001.027.001 (Box Volume 27)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Hay Fever, 1936 -- 1937; UA068.001.028.001 (Box Volume 28)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Kind Lady, 1936 -- 1937; UA068.001.029.001 (Box Volume 29)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Winterset, 1937 -- 1938; UA068.001.030.001 (Box Volume 30)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Another Language, 1937 -- 1938; UA068.001.031.001 (Box Volume 31)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Wiegenlied, 1938; UA068.001.032.001 (Box 32)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Liliom, 1937 -- 1938; UA068.001.033.001 (Box Volume 33)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Royal Family, 1938 -- 1939; UA068.001.034.001 (Box Volume 34)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Pursuit of Happiness, 1938 -- 1939; UA068.001.035.001 (Box Volume 35)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: High Tor, 1938 -- 1939; UA068.001.036.001 (Box Volume 36)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: R. U. R., 1939 -- 1940; UA068.001.037.001 (Box Volume 37)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Twelth Night, 1939 -- 1940; UA068.001.038.001 (Box Volume 38)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Johnson Over Jordan, 1939 -- 1940; UA068.001.039.001 (Box Volume 39)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Margin for Error, 1940 -- 1941; UA068.001.040.001 (Box Volume 40)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Thunder Rock, 1940 -- 1941; UA068.001.041.001 (Box Volume 41)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Male Animal, 1940 -- 1941; UA068.001.042.001 (Box Volume 42)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: It Can't Happen Here, 1938 -- 1939; UA068.001.043.001 (Box Volume 43)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Abraham Lincoln, 1941 -- 1942; UA068.001.044.001 (Box Volume 44)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Heavenly Express, 1941 -- 1942; UA068.001.045.001 (Box Volume 45)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Out of the Frying Pan, 1941 -- 1942; UA068.001.046.001 (Box Volume 46)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Heaven Can Wait, 1942 -- 1943; UA068.001.047.001 (Box Volume 47)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Wuthering Heights, 1942 -- 1943; UA068.001.048.001 (Box Volume 48)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Welcome, Stranger, 1942 -- 1943; UA068.001.049.001 (Box Volume 49)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Goodbye Again, 1943; UA068.001.050.001 (Box Volume 50)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Night Must Fall, 1943; UA068.001.051.001 (Box Volume 51)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Jim Dandy, 1943 -- 1944; UA068.001.052.001 (Box Volume 52)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Hamlet, 1943 -- 1944; UA068.001.053.001 (Box Volume 53)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Key Largo, 1943 -- 1944; UA068.001.054.001 (Box Volume 54)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Berkeley Square, 1943 -- 1944; UA068.001.055.001 (Box Volume 55)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Drunkard; Hay Fever, 1944; UA068.001.056.001 (Box Volume 56)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Marquise, 1944 -- 1945; UA068.001.057.001 (Box Volume 57)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Right You Are, 1945 -- 1946; UA068.001.058.001 (Box Volume 58)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Of Mice and Men, 1945 -- 1946; UA068.001.059.001 (Box Volume 59)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Claudia, 1945 -- 1946; UA068.001.060.001 (Box Volume 60)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Postscript, 1945 -- 1946; UA068.001.061.001 (Box Volume 61)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Skin of Our Teeth, 1946 -- 1947; UA068.001.062.001 (Box Volume 62)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Hotel Universe, 1946 -- 1947; UA068.001.063.001 (Box Volume 63)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Three Men on a Horse, 1946 -- 1947; UA068.001.064.001 (Box Volume 64)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Antigone; The Long Christmas Dinner, 1946 -- 1947; UA068.001.065.001 (Box Volume 65)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Taming of the Shrew, 1947 -- 1948; UA068.001.066.001 (Box Volume 66)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Bury the Dead, 1947 -- 1948; UA068.001.067.001 (Box Volume 67)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Dark of the Moon, 1947 -- 1948; UA068.001.068.001 (Box Volume 68)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Biography, 1947 -- 1948; UA068.001.069.001 (Box Volume 69)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Devils Disciple, 1948 -- 1949; UA068.001.070.001 (Box Volume 70)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Steamship Tenacity, 1948 -- 1949; UA068.001.071.001 (Box Volume 71)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Chief Thing, 1948 -- 1949; UA068.001.072.001 (Box Volume 72)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Miss Julie, 1948 -- 1949; UA068.001.073.001 (Box Volume 73)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Devil and Daniel Webster; Down in the Valley, 1949 -- 1950; UA068.001.074.001 (Box Volume 74)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: She Stoops to Conquer, 1949 -- 1950; UA068.001.075.001 (Box Volume 75)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Excursion, 1950 -- 1951; UA068.001.076.001 (Box Volume 76)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Three's a Company, 1950 -- 1951; UA068.001.077.001 (Box Volume 77)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Beggars in Paradise, 1949 -- 1950; UA068.001.078.001 (Box Volume 78)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: You Never Can Tell, 1950 -- 1951; UA068.001.079.001 (Box Volume 79)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Adding Machine, 1951 -- 1952; UA068.001.080.001 (Box Volume 80)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Ah, Wilderness, 1951 -- 1952; UA068.001.081.001 (Box Volume 81)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Captain Jinks of the Horse Marines, 1951 -- 1952; UA068.001.082.001 (Box Volume 82)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Fashion or Life in New York, 1951 -- 1952; UA068.001.083.001 (Box Volume 83)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Traitor, 1952 -- 1953; UA068.001.084.001 (Box Volume 84)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Time of Your Life, 1952 -- 1953; UA068.001.085.001 (Box Volume 85)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Inspector General, 1952 -- 1953; UA068.001.086.001 (Box Volume 86)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: An Enemy of the People, 1951; UA068.001.087.001 (Box Volume 87)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Glass Menagerie, 1953 -- 1954; UA068.001.088.001 (Box Volume 88)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Twelfth Night, 1953 -- 1954; UA068.001.089.001 (Box Volume 89)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: A Connecticut Yankee, 1953 -- 1954; UA068.001.090.001 (Box Volume 90)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Country Girl, 1953 -- 1954; UA068.001.091.001 (Box Volume 91)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Flies, 1954 -- 1955; UA068.001.092.001 (Box Volume 92)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Importance of Being Earnest, 1954 -- 1955; UA068.001.093.001 (Box Volume 93)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Lady in the Dark, 1954 -- 1955; UA068.001.094.001 (Box Volume 94)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Knight of the Burning Pestle, 1955 -- 1956; UA068.001.095.001 (Box Volume 95)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Man and Superman, 1955 -- 1956; UA068.001.096.001 (Box Volume 96)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Druid Circle, 1955 -- 1956; UA068.001.097.001 (Box Volume 97)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: He Who Gets Slapped, 1956 -- 1957; UA068.001.098.001 (Box Volume 98)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Rivals, 1956 -- 1957; UA068.001.099.001 (Box Volume 99)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Midnight Cry, 1956 -- 1957; UA068.001.100.001 (Box Volume 100)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Doll's House, 1957 -- 1958; UA068.001.101.001 (Box Volume 101)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Merchant of Venice, 1957 -- 1958; UA068.001.102.001 (Box Volume 102)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Arms and the Man, 1957 -- 1958; UA068.001.103.001 (Box Volume 103)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: The Crucible, 1958 -- 1959; UA068.001.104.001 (Box Volume 104)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: King Richard II, 1958 -- 1959; UA068.001.105.001 (Box Volume 105)
  - P.P.P. Play Book: Electra, 1958 -- 1959; UA068.001.106.001 (Box Volume 106)
  - P.P.P. Prompt Books, 1912 -- 1917; UA068.001.107
    - Hi Jinks, 1912; UA068.001.107.00001 (Box 107)
    - Little Brother Ego, Act I, 1914; UA068.001.107.00002 (Box 107)
    - Little Brother Ego, Act II, 1914; UA068.001.107.00003 (Box 107)
    - The Snowball, Act I, 1915; UA068.001.107.00004 (Box 107)
    - The Snowball, Act II, 1915; UA068.001.107.00005 (Box 107)
    - The Snowball, Act III, 1915; UA068.001.107.00006 (Box 107)
    - La Question d'Argent (The Money Question), Act I, 1915; UA068.001.107.00007 (Box 107)
    - La Question d'Argent (The Money Question), Act II, 1915; UA068.001.107.00008 (Box 107)
    - Paul and Virginia, 1916; UA068.001.107.00009 (Box 107)
    - Are Your Hands Tied?, 1916; UA068.001.107.00010 (Box 107)
    - Sweethearts, 1917; UA068.001.107.00011 (Box 107)
  - P.P.P. Productions, 1911 -- 1935; UA068.001.108
    - Lost, A Chaperone, 1911; UA068.001.108.00001 (Box 108)
    - Teamwork, 1911; UA068.001.108.00002 (Box 108)
    - An Enemy of the People, Acts 1-3, 1912 -- 1913; UA068.001.108.00003 (Box 108)
    - An Enemy of the People, Acts 4-5, 1912 -- 1913; UA068.001.108.00004 (Box 108)
    - The Money Question, 1914 -- 1915; UA068.001.108.00005 (Box 108)
    - The Lucky One, 1921; UA068.001.108.00006 (Box 108)
    - The Valiant; Flitch of Bacon; Fame and the Poet, 1922; UA068.001.108.00007 (Box 108)
    - R.U.R., 1923; UA068.001.108.00008 (Box 108)
    - Wedding Bells, 1924; UA068.001.108.00009 (Box 108)
    - Wise Old Neptune, 1926; UA068.001.108.00010 (Box 108)
    - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels programs and clippings, 1928 -- 1935; UA068.001.108.00011 (Box 108)
  - Photographs, 1940 -- 1959; UA068.001.109
    - Johnson over Jordan, 1940; UA068.001.109.00001 (Box 109)
    - Margin for Error, 1940; UA068.001.109.00002 (Box 109)
    - The Male Animal, 1940 -- 1941; UA068.001.109.00003 (Box 109)
    - Thunder Rock, 1941; UA068.001.109.00004 (Box 109)
    - Abraham Lincoln, 1941 -- 1942; UA068.001.109.00005 (Box 109)
    - Heavenly Express, 1941 -- 1942; UA068.001.109.00006 (Box 109)
    - Out of the Frying Pan, 1941 -- 1942; UA068.001.109.00007 (Box 109)
    - Heaven Can Wait, 1942 -- 1943; UA068.001.109.00008 (Box 109)
    - Welcome, Stranger, 1942 -- 1943; UA068.001.109.00009 (Box 109)
    - Key Largo, 1943 -- 1944; UA068.001.109.00010 (Box 109)
    - Berkeley Square, 1943 -- 1944; UA068.001.109.00011 (Box 109)
    - Hamlet, 1943 -- 1944; UA068.001.109.00012 (Box 109)
    - The Drunkard, 1944; UA068.001.109.00013 (Box 109)
    - Hay Fever, 1944; UA068.001.109.00014 (Box 109)
    - Beyond the Horizon, 1944 -- 1945; UA068.001.109.00015 (Box 109)
    - The Marquise, 1944 -- 1945; UA068.001.109.00016 (Box 109)
    - Of Mice and Men, 1945 -- 1946; UA068.001.109.00017 (Box 109)
    - Claudia, 1945 -- 1946; UA068.001.109.00018 (Box 109)
    - Postscript, 1945 -- 1946; UA068.001.109.00019 (Box 109)
    - The Skin of Our Teeth, 1946 -- 1947; UA068.001.109.00020 (Box 109)
    - Hotel Universe, 1946 -- 1947; UA068.001.109.00021 (Box 109)
    - Three Men on a Horse, 1946 -- 1947; UA068.001.109.00022 (Box 109)
    - Antigone, 1947; UA068.001.109.00023 (Box 109)
    - The Taming of the Shrew, 1947 -- 1948; UA068.001.109.00024 (Box 109)
    - Bury the Dead, 1947 -- 1948; UA068.001.109.00025 (Box 109)
    - Dark of the Moon, 1948; UA068.001.109.00026 (Box 109)
    - Devil's Disciple, 1948; UA068.001.109.00027 (Box 109)
    - S.S. Tenacity, 1949; UA068.001.109.00028 (Box 109)
    - The Chief Thing, 1949; UA068.001.109.00029 (Box 109)
    - Miss Julie, 1949; UA068.001.109.00030 (Box 109)
    - The Wedding Morning, 1949; UA068.001.109.00031 (Box 109)
    - The Devil and Daniel Webster, 1949 -- 1950; UA068.001.109.00032 (Box 109)
    - Down in the Valley, 1949 -- 1950; UA068.001.109.00033 (Box 109)
    - She Stoops to Conquer, 1949 -- 1950; UA068.001.109.00034 (Box 109)
    - Beggars in Paradise, 1950; UA068.001.109.00035 (Box 109)
    - Excursion, 1950; UA068.001.109.00036 (Box 109)
    - Three's Company, 1950; UA068.001.109.00037 (Box 109)
    - An Enemy of the People, 1951; UA068.001.109.00038 (Box 109)
    - You Never Can Tell, 1951; UA068.001.109.00039 (Box 109)
    - The Adding Machine, 1951; UA068.001.109.00040 (Box 109)
    - Ah, Wilderness, 1952; UA068.001.109.00041 (Box 109)